MATUZALEM ('MAT') MULLER DOS SANTOS

Los Angeles, CA, US / matuzalemtech@gmail.com

GitHub.com/matuzalemmuller / LinkedIn.com/in/matuzalemmuller / matuzalemmuller.com

M.Sc. in Automation and Systems eng. and Site Reliability Engineer. Eager to improve people's lives through technology.

Site Reliability Engineer with +6 years of experience working with technical support, remote servers maintenance (Linux), AWS (EC2 and S3), Docker, Terraform, and GitLab CI/CD.

EDUCATION

Federal University of Santa Catarina (UFSC), Florianópolis, SC, Brazil

Mar 2020 - Feb 2022

M.Sc. in Automation and Systems Engineering

Thesis: BDI Agent-Oriented Programming in Embedded Systems

Published paper: Directions for implementing BDI agents in embedded systems with limited hardware resources

Federal Institute of Santa Catarina (IFSC), São José, SC, Brazil

Mar 2012 - Dec 2019

B.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering

University of California Santa Barbara (UCSB), Santa Barbara, CA, USA

Jun 2015 - Aug 2016

Electrical Engineering, non-degree international student, Brazil Scientific Mobility Program (BSMP)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Site Reliability Engineer, ElephantDrive Inc (Los Angeles, CA, US)

Sep 2021 – Present

- Create and maintain GitLab CI/CD pipelines to automate software development, testing, and release;
- Manage and monitor AWS infrastructure using Terraform, AWS Console, Grafana, Prometheus, ELK, and others;
- Contribute to designing the development roadmap for client applications (mobile, desktop, and NAS) and website;
- Coordinate software releases with strategic partners and publish new software versions to App Stores.

Technical Specialist & Market Development Consultant, ElephantDrive Inc (Brazil, remote)

Jun 2016 - Aug 2021

- Maintained remote infrastructure used for testing and building client applications, with Windows, Linux, and NAS servers;
- Performed manual and automated testing and quality assurance tasks for websites and client applications on Windows, macOS, Ubuntu, and NAS. Tests mainly were manual, but also programmed tests for the websites using the Selenium package for Java;
- Contributed to designing the development roadmap for client applications (mobile, desktop, and NAS) and website;
- Provided supports level 1 and 2 in Brazil and level 2 worldwide: +7500 tickets resolved with 92% "Good" satisfaction rate in the ticketing platform.

SKILLS

Advanced: Python, Linux (+10 years of daily usage and +6 years of server maintenance), SSH, Git, GitLab CI, Bash.

Intermediate: C/C++, Docker, GitHub Actions, LaTeX, Jira, Networking, AWS, Terraform, Prometheus, Granada, Project Management.

Basic: MATLAB, Java, MySQL, Jenkins, Kubernetes, GCP, OCI.

Language: native Portuguese, fluent English.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Honors: BSMP, full scholarship to study abroad, funded by the Brazilian government.

Certificate: Uncomplicating Docker. Apr 2022.

Certificate: Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2021 Associate. Feb 2022.

Certificate: GitLab Certified Associate. Jan 2022.

Certificate: Mutirão DevOps. Dec 2021. 7 months long DevOps training. Certificate: Specialization: AWS Fundamentals. AWS. 4 Courses. Aug 2020.

Certificate: Technical Support Fundamentals. Google. Jul 2020.